A red fire burns ablaze,
Don't lose, stand up,
AUGUST 7TH, 2003 (THURSDAY)
I promise to make the tears stop,
Wonder, Wonder, such a kind heart,
Embracing you,
His loving heart is his weapon,
A hero who protects--
Yes, this is what happens with records.
Good morning, Satoru.
We need to avoid risk.
But you can't be afraid of it.
Being able to freely operate
without fearing risk is our advantage.
Is that why you never started a family?
Yeah.
But I don't regret it.
Even if I'm not rewarded for it
anytime soon.
SACHIKO
HE'S AWAKE.
No.
I'm sure your reward...
is coming soon.
Hello?
AUGUST 21ST, 2003 (THURSDAY)
How about we try moving your hand?
First, let's start
by trying to bend both elbows.
Good.
Next, could you try
turning your head my way?
Okay, now the other side.
Good.
I'm impressed to see you move this much
after only being awake for two weeks.
That is thanks to your mother.
She spent four hours every day
taking care of you.
That is why your muscles
haven't atrophied to hopeless levels.
Normally, when you've been asleep
for 15 years...
Fif...
teen...
years?
Fif...
teen...
years...
Please bring the results to me
as soon as you get them.
-Yes, doctor.
-Should I take this to the doctor?
AUGUST 25TH, 2003 (MONDAY)
Ma'am, I would like to begin
questioning him.
Is that all right?
Please take good care of him.
Satoru...
before you fell asleep,
what is the newest memory
you can remember?
Newest?
Let me rephrase that.
What's the last thing you remember?
Mom.
Where's my flute?
Even I knew
that this wasn't my last memory.
And it was just then
that I realized for the first time
that there were holes
in my memory.
Then... I think it's time
we have him meet them.
Yes.
Satoru.
You have visitors.
Thank you for waiting.
Please come in.
Satoru.
Good morning.
I'm your old classmate,
Kenya Kobayashi.
I'm Hiromi Sugita.
You look well, Satoru.
You both got old.
-Did you come all the way from Hokkaido?
-No.
We've moved to Tokyo, too.
I see.
So, you're both working in Tokyo now?
Yeah.
I became a lawyer
like I always said I would.
I'm a doctor.
Although, I'm still an intern.
That's really amazing.
-By the way, Satoru, I wanted to ask--
-Kenya!
What would you like to drink?
I'm buying.
That's not necessary.
We should be going, anyway.
We don't want to tire Satoru too much.
Oh, okay.
Well, Satoru...
Bye.
Thank you for coming all this way
to see him again.
Our pleasure.
Here.
I've compiled everything
that has happened to Satoru.
If someday Satoru wants to know,
I thought it could be useful.
Thank you.
It was nothing.
But... if you decide it's best to
throw it away, I would understand.
You were the one who was able
to get Satoru to wake up, after all.
We will come again.
I distinctly feel like
a piece of me is missing.
But...
if my mother thinks
it should stay forgotten,
then I guess I could live
with never remembering.
Satoru!
Kayo.
Congratulations.
I got married, and I'm Kayo Sugita now.
Sugita?
Wait, did you marry Hiromi?
So, that's why Hiromi looked like
he wanted to tell me something.
What's the baby's name?
Mirai.
Mirai?
That's a good name.
To be honest, some part of me
didn't feel right about it.
Like is it really fair for us
to go on and be happy?
Even when your coma
could have been because of me.
It felt like
we were deserting you.
Kayo.
My fate is my own.
There's no reason
for you to feel responsible.
The reason I'm like this now...
must be the result of something I wanted.
You really are amazing, Satoru.
You've been asleep for 15 years,
but you can still say
something so wonderful.
It's nothing special.
But still...
the reason that little girl
who could only imagine being alone
was able to grow up
to have a family like this...
is because of you, Satoru.
Thank you.
I felt a strange feeling
inside myself,
and I had to look into it.
Yes?
I'd like to try sketching
for my rehabilitation.
Could I borrow a pencil and some paper?
Of course.
I'll get those to you right away.
How am I able to draw a picture like this?
How far are you into
the Wonder Guy volumes?
I'm on volume three.
Mom.
You didn't tell Kayo not to talk, did you?
Why not?
I didn't realize you noticed.
To tell you the truth...
after Kenya and Hiromi left...
I felt like I made a mistake.
That they didn't get to say
what they wanted to.
Even though they came to see you
after waiting 15 years.
I was here talking to you every day...
but when you talked back
your voice had changed.
It's the first time I felt
that you'd grown.
I was really happy.
You're an adult already.
Here.
TO MY DEAR FRIEND, SATORU FUJINUMA
Kenya brought it in.
I think... it will tell you
what you want to know.
Are you sure?
To be honest...
I'm a little scared.
But...
when a child
becomes interested in something...
it's the parent's duty to support them.
Satoru.
It could be that
you won't need these files
for your future.
But... if you ever became curious
about what happened to you,
I put this together
hoping you'd find it useful.
The day you came into contact
with your own case
was March 14th, 1988.
You were discovered
in a lake near the city.
At around 6:30 p.m...
you were rescued by a veterinarian
passing the area.
You were in cardiac arrest.
Your body temperature
was under 82 degrees Fahrenheit.
It's okay! You're okay!
An ambulance is on the way!
Don't give up! Don't give up!
-Doctor.
-Patient's condition?
Mr. Satoru Fujinuma.
JCS level is 100. Breathing is shallow.
We put him on oxygen.
Mr. Fujinuma!
His temperature is 93.2 degrees.
He's experiencing hypothermia.
The hospital's doctor
hypothesized the low water temperature
allowed the brain to enter a state
of suspended animation,
avoiding brain death.
And so...
you slept for 15 years.
Almost ironically, you were able to prove
the serial kidnapper and murderer
you talked about was present in our town
by becoming a victim yourself.
Your case
launched a large investigation
as an attempted murder investigation.
Despite this,
they were unable to find
any leads on a suspect.
But for your case,
there was no suspect to take the fall,
as the killer always
so carefully arranged.
I believe the reason for that is this:
Your very existence
interfered with the killer's plans.
It became difficult to continue
your treatment in Hokkaido.
So, in July of 1989,
you were transferred to a hospital in
Chiba capable of offering long-term care.
But still there was no sign of recovery,
so some time later,
they switched you to home care.
We are raising money
for Satoru Fujinuma's treatment.
Thank you!
We are raising money
for our friend Satoru Fujinuma!
Thank you!
Wanting to help any way we could,
we started collecting donations.
We actually still do this even now.
Does it sound like
I'm asking for a thank-you?
Believe me, I'm not.
Back then,
you were our hero.
We wanted to catch up to you.
We wanted to fight with you.
You helped us become who we are.
YOUR FRIEND, KENYA KOBAYASHI
It's the first time I learned
how good it feels...
to not be alone.
I more or less understood
what happened to me in the past.
But... there are memories
I can't remember
that aren't written in here.
COURTESY OF THE
NISHIFUNABASHI CITY COUNCIL
I better make it to the end,
or I'll lose face.
That was really amazing, mister!
I see, Kumi.
So, your surgery is next month.
They said that will fix me.
But, you know, I'm scared.
Then do you want me to tell you
the secret to being brave?
What?
You imagine the smile
of someone important to you.
Of course, you have to smile, too.
Okay.
I'll try it.
His body is grown,
but his mind is still a child's.
I like the sound of that!
This was worth the trouble!
What the hell are you doing?!
You stupid?
Don't force that nonsense on the camera.
The camera doesn't lie.
I'm sorry for the commotion.
How is it possible?
I know this girl somehow.
Don't let her leave.
Talk to her.
Thank you.
I should be the one apologizing.
Are you okay?
He's the one at fault.
So, I don't think he'd press charges.
I mean your hand.
It hurts a little.
I punched him real hard.
But my motto is to go all in
when I see something happening
in front of me.
Go all in...?
That's a really nice motto.
What?
Really?
There aren't many people
who would say that.
I just can't stand anyone
using the camera like that.
I have a dream!
You have to ask her about it.
What is your dream?
I want to take pictures!
I really love the sky.
I'd go all over Japan,
or all around the world,
just traveling with my camera.
Airi...
Mister?
What's wrong, mister?
-What's wrong?
-Mister!
-Are you okay, can you hear me?
-Are you okay? Mister!
-Are you okay? Are you okay?
-Mister?
Subtitle translation by
Zensho Yamamoto